<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English on ΕΜΒΡΥΙΚΗ ΝΕΥΡΟΛΟΓΙΑ / Παναγιώτης Μπεναρδής</title><link>https://pbenardis.github.io/categories/english/</link><description>Recent content in English on ΕΜΒΡΥΙΚΗ ΝΕΥΡΟΛΟΓΙΑ / Παναγιώτης Μπεναρδής</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us, el</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:36:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pbenardis.github.io/categories/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>English</title><link>https://pbenardis.github.io/p/english/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 06:36:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pbenardis.github.io/p/english/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://pbenardis.github.io/p/english/english.jpg" alt="Featured image of post English" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the website of Mr. Panagiotis Benardis, Consultant in Obstetrics and Gynecology, specialised in Fetal Medicine and Gynecological Ultrasound.
He is the holder of Diploma in Fetal Medicine (FMF, London) and IOTA Certificate (IOTA Group, Leuven, Belgium).
He is the Head of the Fetal Neurology Department of IASO Hospital, Athens, Greece.
Bio: &lt;a class="link" href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/pbenardis/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;https://www.linkedin.com/in/pbenardis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fetal Neurology is the field of Maternal-Fetal Medicine that deals with congenital anomalies of the Central Nervous System (CNS) i.e. the brain and spinal cord of the fetus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fetal neurosonogram is a dedicated ultrasound of the CNS of the fetus. It is performed by a doctor who is specialized in this examination and who can diagnose the majority of fetal CNS anomalies accurately. It is usually performed with a combination of transabdominal and transvaginal imaging, including the use of color Doppler and 3D/4D ultrasound.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A review of pregnant women&amp;rsquo;s medical history and examinations is carried out, and then the neurosonogram is performed, based on which the assessment for the diagnosis is provided. The need for additional examinations (genetic testing, magnetic resonance imaging, lab tests for infections etc) is assessed and at the end all the data is collected and, with the aid of a pediatric neurologist, an accurate diagnosis and prognosis is provided. The parents and the treating physician are informed about the short-term and long-term prognosis, in order to have the best possible insight on their pregnancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indications for a fetal neurosonogram are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspected CNS anomaly on the routine ultrasound scan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspected CNS anomaly on the nuchal translucency scan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Family history of hereditary CNS anomaly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous pregnancy with CNS anomaly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monochorionic twins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fetus with congenital heart anomaly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suspected congenital infection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure to medication possibly associated with CNS anomalies (including both parents)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variants of unknown significance on a cromosome microarray analysis result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inadequate visualisation of the CNS in previous ultrasound scans due to maternal high Body Mass Index (BMI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parental request&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a class="link" href="mailto:pbenardis@proton.me" &gt;pbenardis@proton.me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mob: +30 6945779539&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In order to book an appointment, all previous tests (ultrasounds, genetic tests, MRI, blood tests, etc.) should be sent to the doctor in advance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>